Yannish Sewraz



ABOUT ME

My name is Yannish Sewraz and this is my resume. Rather than list all of the things I "can do", I decided to write, candidly, the highlights of my experiences at various stages of my professional career. I did succumb to peer pressure and feel the need to write a "skills" section but everything beyond that is genuine, I promise.

SKILLS	
Python	••••
SQL	••••
Excel Includes VBA	••••
Javascript	• • • • •
LANGUAGES	
English	••••
French	••••
Spanish	••••

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

WatrHub Inc., Data Team Lead

May 2018 – present | Toronto, ON

My mandate as Data Team Lead at WatrHub is to deliver data to clients, maintain the data in our warehouse and identify new data that can be added to said warehouse. Data, data, data. I lead a team of 4 to that end. Like many management roles, my day-to-day varies wildly but generally revolves around meeting with client, working with my team on data projects and writing code.

WatrHub Inc., Business Intelligence Analyst

Sep 2017 – May 2018 | Toronto, ON

In this role, I focused heavily on data analysis and creating visuals to help WatrHub better understand its processes and workflows. I attempted to build a CRM to track sales, cleaned and analyzed data in pandas (a Python library) and visualized it in Plotly (another Python library). It was a short stint that helped me learn a lot about Python, Jupyter, pandas and plotly.

WatrHub Inc., Back-End Data Analyst

Feb 2017 – Sep 2017 | Toronto, ON

This was my first role at WatrHub. I was hired as a research analyst that completed reports for clients based on their requirements. At a highlevel, my job was to conduct searches using our internal search engine and identify promising sales opportunities for clients in the water industry. This involved learning about a variety of technical processes and regulations (among other things) in the US water industry.

Gap Year Abroad

Sep 2015 – Aug 2016 | World Travel
I had what some might call a "quarter life crisis" and decided to quit my job and backpack for an indefinite amount of time, which turned out to be roughly one year. It was an amazing experience that took me to India, Thailand, Laos, Vietnam, China, Mongolia and Germany. It taught me to value the important things in life, how to be resourceful, persevere and much, much more.

EDUCATION

University of Waterloo,Bachelor of Environmental Studies
2008 – 2013 | Waterloo, ON